Tel: 07466 818 068

TOM PADMANATHAN

I expect most employers will wonder what benefit they will gain by bringing a 15-year-old into their organisation. After setting up 2 businesses, and progressing my secondary school education, I made a decision last year to not go to University. I have been gaining valuable experience through self-learning and working in a commercial environment. It is imperative that I continue to build my experience in the technology sector. I have a proven record of being a self-starter in the technology positions I have had. I have delivered tangible value which has made a difference to a business. I believe by working at your company and not charging a fee in 2022, I can deliver tangible value with an unnaturally low cost and opportunity cost. My goal is to work with such a company over the next few years; with my workload reducing to part-time levels during term time.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Building two new profitable businesses
- Helping the launch of a new football stadium and configuring new Point of Sale machines for up to 9,000 fans
- Building the technology capability for a new registered charity/museum in London
- Building both client and server and setting up a new secure network
- Providing IT support for office staff
- Self-learning hardware and software technologies (i.e., Operating Linux Processes, Computer Building/Modding, Networking, Crypto Currency, Soldering, HTML, CSS, and a bit of Javascript)

WORK HISTORY

CS:GO Skins Trader

May 2020 - present

At the start of 2020, I began playing a video game called CS:GO. I noticed that a lot of people had expensive "skins" so I deposited £20 into my steam wallet and traded it up to £35. This made me see the potential of the CS:GO skin market. I kept on depositing, buying, selling, and trading for profit. I ended up making more than £2,000 and still my current inventory value is £1,700. I've enjoyed the process this new venture provides me with a steady income stream.

WiSH Software Engineer July 2021–present https://wimbledoninsportinghistory.org/

Brought on as the first technical resource at a newly formed charity. This was a full-time role based in their offices and this reverted to a part-time role from September 2021. Working with the Head of Marketing and Head of Operations, several of technical projects were completed; including:

- Architecting, building, and maintaining a new website in WordPress
- Taking and curating new media at special events and updating all WiSH online infrastructure
- Setting up corporate email and cloud document repository to improve efficiency
- Building and managing a new Help Desk function

Tom's Bazaar Owner / Entertainer 2014 – 2020

www.tomsbazaar.com

When I was six, I went to Sri Lanka and bought £14 worth of pepper then when I came back to England sold it and made a profit of £13. A year later, I learned to make animal balloons, bracelets, and origami and sold these at car boot sales together with toys I bought from China. Tom's Bazaar now has stalls at Primary School fairs and organises children's

Tel: 07466 818 068

parties. In 2017, I had several stalls at school fairs, serviced birthday parties, and even had one corporate customer. We also created a logo, branding, a website, and templates for proposals and integrated electronic payments.

EDUCATION

1	Saint Cecilias Church of England	I Will be starting G.C.S.E subjects in September 2021 with a major focus on Computing
2	Wimbledon Park Primary School	SATS: 91% in English Reading 92% in SPAG and 94% in Mathematics.
3	Wimbledon Rugby Club	I captained the U8 team in the semi-final to reach the final of the Northampton rugby
		tournament.
4	Enterprise	Have gained steady income from my two commercial ventures
5	Music	I started playing the guitar in August 2017 and composed "My Music" which I sang at
		Saint Cecilia's music scholarship. My 63% was not enough and I was nervous.

LEISURE INTERESTS

1	Cooking	I enjoy cooking. I have been taught by chefs in commercial restaurants to gain experience.
2	Woodwork	I love wood and have a workbench so I can work on woodcraft projects.
3	Fitness	I completed a David Lloyd swimming challenge in 2010 when I swam 52 lengths. In 2012 I completed a running challenge and ran a mile a day for 6 months. I completed the London to Brighton bike ride when I was 10 and again at 11 (this time I rode the Ditchling Beacon without stopping). In 2019, I cycled through Switzerland, Germany, and Austria with a backpack (200 miles in 5 days).
4	AFC Wimbledon	First game in 2010. Pitch team volunteer in 2013. WiSH Founder member and responsible for their IT infrastructure
5	Technology	I love technology and built my own computer self-learning from YouTube. In 2019, I built my first website for a fun business called; Dr. Chapati – providing chapatis for £1 to school friends for their lunch.

REFERENCES

Peter Leng, Head of Marketing, WiSH:

"Tom Padmanathan has been working since July 2021 as a volunteer at Wimbledon in Sporting History (WiSH) - principally looking after its IT services - and is a trusted, valued and highly competent member of the WiSH team.

In the summer of 2021 Tom concentrated on designing and installing a new website for WiSH, which ensured the charity had a properly functioning and impressive portal to the outside world. Tom has set up WiSH email accounts for WiSH volunteers with an IT support desk to troubleshoot any IT issues.

Tom also helps out on the communications side of the charity, taking photographs and recording video at major launch events which are an integral part of the WiSH comms team's publicity work. He combines this with updating the website with news features that are provided but which he ensures look professional on delivery to the website.

Tom gets on with tasks assigned to him diligently, methodically and always to a very good standard. He is quiet but committed and always happy to ask for advice or help when needed. Tom has been and is a real asset to Wimbledon in Sporting History, and I have no hesitation in recommending him as a reliable, honest and hardworking young man".

Chris Mappley, IT Director, AFC Wimbledon:

"The history books will show, that as we accelerated to open the new stadium, there was one all important task to do; enable electronic payments. Thanks, Tom, for helping thousands of people to buy their lunch!"

Miss Davis, Director, Free Spirited (December 2017):

"Free Spirited provides yoga to children in schools. At the end of term, I always like to present the children with a little gift, to thank them for their participation. With nearly 30 children in a class, it is quite a task for me to get these, but with Tom's unique service it was a breeze for me this term. He came up with some great suggestions for gifts and delivered them on time and at a very reasonable price. The children were very happy! An amazing service from someone so young".

EDUCATIONAL REFERENCES

Mrs. Simpson, Head of Computer Science, Saint Cecilias Church of England School (July 2021):

Although I have only known Tom since I arrived at Saint Cecilia's this year, his reputation for being a thoughtful and conscientious student was relayed to me from his past tutors. Tom has a caring and sensitive nature that initially comes across as shy and quiet but hides his patient and tolerant nature. He has impressed me with his thirst for knowledge and understanding of coding in particular, having clearly taught himself a range of coding skills that demonstrated his prior Python knowledge. He has a good memory for factual information so is easily able to learn supporting facts and theory behind applications. If I have to find a small fault with Tom it was his struggle with the demands of remote learning and homework submission during lockdown at the start of this year, where his grades dropped to a level C (level 4). However, he has worked hard and has enjoyed his coding unit this term, restoring his grade to a B (level 7) predicted GCSE Computer Science End of Year 11 Grade. I confidently commend him as a young man of considerable potential that will do well from the work experience scheme you are offering him.

Miss Brunt, Year 6, Wimbledon Park Primary School (July 2018):

"Tom is a quiet, sensitive and friendly boy. He is aware of those around him and is always prepared to encourage and support anybody in whatever they do. Tom has built a reputation s for being a 'good guy' due to his positive, generous and laid-back nature. Academically, Tom has proven this year to be determined, focused and able. When working both in class and in smaller groups, Tom's contribution is always valuable. Continuing into Secondary school with this outstanding attitude towards his peers and his learning will only lead to great success".

